WADIH OJEIL

Orlando, FL 32828

Phone: (407)463-6548 | Email: wadih.ojeil@gmail.com <u>LinkedIn</u>: https://www.linkedin.com/in/wadih-ojeil/ | Github: https://github.com/wojeil/ | Portfolio: https://wojeil.github.io/my-portfolio-with-react

SUMMARY

Full stack developer and a former Deputy Sheriff with experience and passion in front and back end development. A deep knowledge in Javascript, HTML, CSS, MySQL, MongoDb, IndexDb, PWA, Node.js, JQuery, REACT, Bootstrap and Bulma Framework. Adept at taking challenges and solving problems with demonstrated leadership through team building and people skills. Highly trained to produce results in stressful situations and take necessary actions required to complete tasks.

TECHNICAL SKILLS.

Programming Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JS, MySQL, MongoDb.

Technologies: Node.js, REACT.js, Bootstrap, Bulma, JQuery, Mongoose ORM, API's. **Languages:** English(Native), French(Native), Arabic(Native), Spanish(Limited Working).

PROJECTS

Employee Tracker | https://github.com/wojeil/Employee Tracker | Fork and Run Node

- **Summary:** Full CRUD prompt-based node application that helps the User create his/her own employee database dynamically via JS in MySQL.
- Core responsibilities: Created and delivered a node application.
- **Tools and languages:** Node.js, Inquirer.js, Console-Table-Printer, Asciiart-Logo, MySQL and JS.

NoteTaker|https://github.com/wojeil/Note_Taker|https://mighty-sea-99609.herokuapp.com/

- Summary: Full CRUD application that allows User to save, update and delete notes.
- Core responsibilities: Crean application with Express is within the given due date.
- Tools and languages: Bootstrap, Node.js, Express.js, JQuery, HTML5, CSS3, JS.

The HUB | https://github.com/wojeil/HUB | https://gentle-sea-35926.herokuapp.com/

- **Summary:** MERN application that enhances communication and time-management between admins and their Users. Best applied for the workplace environment and could be applied with friends of common interest.
- Core responsibilities: As Project Manager, managed tasks through GitHub Kanban Board; created both dashboard pages with Front-End and Delete with Back-End CRUD. Designed and created weekly planner and planner search page with Front-End CRUD and minor Back-End fixes. Worked with my team to conduct wireframes for all pages including DB set-up with Mongoose ORM through Robo3t.
- **Tools and languages:** BootStrap, Mongoose ORM, Express.js, REACT, Node.js, Passport.js, Axios, JSX, HTML5, CSS3, JS.

EXPERIENCE

Freelance Full-Stack Developer Self-Employed

06/2020 - Present

Orlando, FL

Create, fix, develop and update websites for small businesses. Provide private tutoring for students who are enrolled in school to learn how to code.

- Creator of Byblos Hookah Lounge website with the use of REACT, Node.js and Express.js.
- Expanded my knowledge and still currently learning new technologies.

Deputy Sheriff Orange County Sheriff's Office

07/2016 - 01/2020

Orlando, FL

Prepare formal reports and general investigation for criminal prosecution. Write and execute search warrants. Patrol and testify in criminal trials. Process and catalog evidence. Manage/Triage workload.

- Entrusted with Ride A Longs and two UCF interns that have recently been hired by the agency.
- Lead in a successful narcotics search warrant with no prior experience.

Guest Service Associate Racetrac Petroleum

10/2012 - 07/2016

Orlando, FL

Ring up guests on the cash register and balance cash and inventory transactions. Resolve guest complaints. Update prices and post new signage to reflect monthly promotions and sales opportunities. All keep a positive attitude.

- Learned how to communicate with multiple people from different cultures and backgrounds.
- Upsold many guests with promotional products that helped the store increase profits.

Student Intern United States Postal Inspection Service

01/2015 - 04/2015

Orlando, FL

Shadow special agents and assist them when solving cases. Sort evidence data in spreadsheets Screen incoming mail through USPS.

- Received a Certificate of Appreciation.
- Earned university credits.

EDUCATION

Bootcamp Certificate: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

A 12-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Security Management Certification: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

Bachelor of Science in Criminal Justice: University of Central Florida, Orlando, FL

Associate of Arts in General Studies: Valencia College, Orlando, FL